<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--Arbortext, Inc., 1988-2011, v.4002-->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC  "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
 "concept.dtd">
<?Pub Sty _display FontColor="red"?>
<?Pub Inc?>
<concept id="pl00140_" xml:lang="en-us">
<title>Configuring the sample MQTT iRule </title>
<shortdesc>This sample iRule reads an iFile which contains a pre-defined client/server mapping, for device routing, that the administrator has already determined.</shortdesc>
<conbody>
<section>
<p>The format of the iFile is as follows:<ul>
<li>&lt;regular expression> &lt;comma separated list of IBM MessageSight server IP addresses> &lt;dest port></li>
</ul></p>
<p>The following is an example iFile that works with client IDs generated by mqttbench: <codeblock>
ser111_c.* 192.0.2.0,192.0.2.12 16901
ser112_c.* 192.0.2.7,192.0.2.34 16901
ser410_c.* 192.0.2.8,192.0.2.35 16901
ser132_c.* 192.0.2.9,192.0.2.36 16901
ser212_c.* 192.0.2.10,192.0.2.37 16901</codeblock></p>
<p>In this example, MQTT devices with client ID starting with ser111_c will first attempt to be routed to 192.0.2.0 on port 16901. If this server is down, then the iRule will attempt to forward the connection to 192.0.2.12 on port 16901. The server list can be arbitrary length. With this iRule design it is not necessary to create Pool or Node configuration objects in BIG-IP.</p>
</section>
<section><title>Importing an iRule for MQTT client affinity</title><p>The following screen shots show how you can import an iFile into the BIG-IP application:<image
      placement="inline" href="PDFiRules17a.jpg" scale="30" scope="" status=""
      alt="Select System>File Management:iFile List" width="400" height="150"/></p>and<p><image
      href="PDFiRules18a.jpg" scale="30"
      alt="Select Import from File Management screen to import the file that you require."
      width="400"/><ul>
      <li>The name of the iFile “serverMap” is hard coded in the iRule and you can import/update the content associated with the iFile.</li>
      <li>F5 BIG-IP command line syntax for modifying an iFile is as follows: <codeph>tmsh modify sys file ifile [ifile-name] source-path <xref
        href="http://192.70.0.1/myifile.txt" format="html" scope="external"
        >http://192.70.0.1/myifile.txt</xref></codeph>  </li>
      <li>When the iFile is modified, the RULE_INIT line in the iRule should be re-invoked by using change/save to the iRule.</li>
      </ul></p></section>
</conbody>
<?tm 1413223986 8?>
</concept>
<?Pub *0000004710?>
